So this is Avancier?
这里就是阿凡锡亚吗
It's a peaceful town.
是个很恬静的城镇呢
That's right.
没错
There isn't much going on in the countryside,
虽然这里是个 什么都没有的乡下地区
but it's a good place to settle down.
但是很适合居住哦
I hope you come to like it too.
要是你也能住得习惯就好了
Rud!
路德
How long are you staying this time?
你这次会在镇上待多久？
If you're not in a hurry, let's take a day just for ourselves.
如果不赶时间 我们两个人找一天去玩吧
Rud.
路德
I didn't know you were returning today.
原来你是今天回来啊
It's been a while, you two.
你们两个 好久不见
What brings you to these parts?
在这里做什么啊
I was on my way to buy a hammer.
我要去买铁槌
Fil was patrolling.
菲尔是在镇上巡逻吧
Yes.
是啊
I checked in on Manicia.
我有去探望玛妮西娅
She is doing well.
她很健康哦
I see.
这样啊
Thank you.
谢谢你们
It's thanks to the townsfolk keeping an eye out for my sister
多亏有镇上的人替我照顾妹妹
that I can go on adventures without worry.
我才能放心地去冒险
No need to thank us.
不用跟我们道谢啦
By the way, who is the little girl?
话说回来 这孩子是谁呀
She's Luna. I met her during my adventures.
这位是我在旅途途中遇到的露娜
She didn't have a place to go,
因为她无处可去 似乎很伤脑筋
so I figured I'd let her stay with me for the time being.
所以我打算先照顾她一段时间
I see.
原来如此
Hello there, Luna.
你好 露娜
I'm the poster girl for the blacksmith, Milena.
我是打铁铺的看板娘 米蕾娜
Nice to meet you.
今后请多指教咯
Your turn.
来 换你
My name is Fil.
那个 我叫做菲尔
I'm the vice leader of the town's vigilante corps.
是镇上自警团的副队长
Fil is shy.
菲尔很怕生的
Don't out me like that, Rud!
别说出来啊 路德
THE STRONGEST TANK'S LABYRINTH RAIDS
《最强肉盾的迷宫攻略～拥有稀少技能体力9999的肉盾，被勇者队伍辞退了》
My little sister might be sleeping.
我妹妹现在可能正在睡觉
We have to be quiet so we don't wake her up.
为了不吵醒她 我们要小声一点
This smell…
这股味道是…
These are my favourite tomato dishes.
全是我喜欢的西红柿料理
Big Brother, welcome home.
哥哥 欢迎回来
Who is this?
这位是？
I'm home, Manicia!
我回来了 玛妮西娅
This is Luna. I met her along my way back.
这位是我在回乡途中遇到的露娜
She ran into some trouble,
因为她遇到一些困难
so I decided to bring her back here for now.
所以我就先把她带回家了
I see.
这样啊
It's been so long since I last saw Manicia.
好久没见到玛妮西娅了
She's still as cute as ever.
怎么可以这么可爱呢
For a moment, I thought a goddess had appeared.
刹那间 我还以为是女神降临了
It's nice to meet you, Miss Luna.
露娜小姐 初次见面
I'm Manicia.
我是玛妮西娅
It isn't anything fancy,
虽然只有粗茶淡饭
but please make yourself at home.
但还请你不用拘束
Thank you…
谢…谢谢您
All right.
好了
Big Brother, you've had a long journey. You must be tired.
哥哥长途跋涉回来 应该也累了吧
Have a seat and eat.
快点坐下来吃饭吧
I'll prepare another portion.
我再多准备一份餐点
Wait.
等等
Your body is frail. You shouldn't push yourself.
你身体不好 不要勉强啦
I feel perfectly fine today, so I'll be all right.
我今天状况很好 所以没问题的
Why don't we prepare it together, then?
那就一起准备吧 好吗
I suppose. Let's do that, then.
说得也是 那就这么办吧
Um…
那…那个
Lady Manicia's hair…
玛妮西娅大人的头发…
Is this your first time seeing someone with unique abilities?
你第一次看到有特异体质的人吗
For Manicia, it's her hair.
玛妮西娅的特异体质在于头发部分
Her hair moves according to her mood.
所以她的头发会像这样 随着情绪起伏摆动
I see.
原来如此
Manicia,
玛妮西娅
seems like you knew I was coming home.
是说你好像早就知道我回来了耶
Is that the effect of the skill?
那是技能的效果吗
Well, something like that.
嗯 虽然只是有种预感而已
Even so, you prepared my favourite dishes for me.
即便只是预感 你还是事先准备了我喜欢的料理
I'm so touched I could cry.
哥哥高兴到都快哭了
You silly.
你是笨蛋吗
You two are very close.
两位的感情很好呢
Isn't this normal?
这样不是很普通吗
Big Brother, please start helping.
哥哥 你也动手帮忙啦
I'm digging in.
我要开动了
Miss Luna.
露娜小姐
The way you hold your spoon is peculiar indeed.
你拿汤匙的方式好奇特哦
I… I'm sorry…
不…不好意思
I've only ever used it a few times…
因为我只用过几次而已
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'll do better.
我下次会好好拿的
-Luna. -It's not necessary to apologise.
-喂 露娜 -你不需要道歉啦
You hold a spoon like this.
汤匙要像这样拿哦
I'll teach you.
我之后会一个一个教你
Let's take it one step at a time.
让我们一起慢慢学习吧
Thank you very much…
真的…很谢谢您
Sir Rud. Lady Manicia.
路德大人 玛妮西娅大人
Good morning.
早安
Did you prepare of all this by yourself?
这些都是你一个人做的吗
Yes.
是的
These are all the dishes Lady Manicia taught me over the past three days.
这些是玛妮西娅大人 这三天教我的所有菜色
Delicious!
好吃
It tastes exactly like the way Manicia prepares it.
跟玛妮西娅煮出来的味道一样
In only a few days,
才短短几天
Luna's mastered all the fundamentals of everyday life.
露娜就已经把所有 日常基本常识全都掌握了
Is this the Homunculus's astounding learning ability?
这就是人造人的超强学习能力吗
Big Brother.
哥哥
The weather is lovely today.
刚好今天天气也不错
You should give Miss Luna a tour of the town.
你带露娜小姐去镇上逛逛吧
Good idea.
说得也是
I'd like to introduce Luna to the townsfolk, so this is a nice opportunity.
我正好想跟大家介绍一下露娜 顺便去逛逛也不错
I'll lend her some of my clothes, then.
那么 把我的外出服借给她吧
I have a few sets that she can wear.
我这边刚好有几件 适合露娜小姐穿的衣服
Manicia is adorable when she acts like a big sister too.
以姐姐自居的玛妮西娅也好可爱哦
But this one might be a little difficult to put on.
不过这件衣服好像有点难穿
I'll help you.
我来帮你穿吧
Sorry…
不…不好意思
I'll do it myself.
我自己来就好
Was it something I did?
我是不是不小心冒犯到她了呢
That was probably a defensive reflex.
她刚才应该是在提防玛妮西娅吧
She didn't want Manicia to see her magic stone.
怕她看到自己身上的魔石
There is no Adventurers' Guild or church in Avancier.
阿凡锡亚没有冒险者公会 也没有教堂
Only a blacksmith and a pharmacy.
只有一间打铁铺和药房
If there's anything that stands out around here,
要说周遭有什么明显的特征
it's probably the orchard.
就是附近有个果园吧
Well, if it isn't Rud.
这不是路德吗
Here to give me grandchildren with my daughter?
你是来跟我女儿生孙子的吗
No, Mr. Regil.
雷吉尔先生 不是啦
Luna, this is Milena's father.
露娜 这位是米蕾娜的爸爸
I've heard about you from Milena.
我听米蕾娜说过了
Nice to meet you, Miss.
请多指教咯 小姑娘
Hello…
请…请多指教
That reminds me, Mr. Regil…
对了 雷吉尔先生
I see.
原来如此
You lost your magic sword.
所以你的魔剑才被人拿走了啊
All right. Seeing as it's a request from Rud,
好 这可是路德的请求
I'll make you a super sword in the shortest amount of time I can.
我会在最短的时间内 做一把超强神剑给你的
Thank you very much.
谢谢您
Mind if I let my daughter help?
我可以让我女儿一起帮忙吗
Her skills are as good as mine.
那家伙像我 手艺也很好
Of course.
当然可以
I'll come back for it when it's ready.
那么 等您完成后 我再过来拿
Wait.
等一下
Why don't you show Luna the magic greens garden?
你带露娜去看看魔菜的菜园吧
Simply put,
简单来说
magic greens are magic-fied vegetables.
魔菜就是魔物版本的蔬菜
They're cultivated by magic,
因为是靠魔力培育
so the harvests are not restricted by seasons
所以收成时间无关季节
and they're high in nutritional value.
而且营养价值也很丰富
It's Rud!
是路德哥哥
And he's got a girlfriend with him.
而且还带着女朋友
She is not my girlfriend.
她不是我的女朋友
Her name is Luna. She's my companion.
她叫做露娜 是我的旅行同伴
Now that I think about it, Rud probably can't get a girlfriend anyway.
仔细想想 路德哥哥确实不可能交女朋友
He has a sister complex, after all.
毕竟他是妹控啊
Where did you learn an archaic term like that?
你们怎么知道那种古代语啊
From Fil.
菲尔姐姐有说过啊
You boys!
你们几个
What are you kids doing here?
在这里摸什么鱼啊
Back to work in the fields!
快给我回田里帮忙
It's Granny Gigi!
是吉吉婆婆
You're as healthy as ever.
您还是这么健朗呢
Oh, it's Rud.
哎呀 路德
Your girlfriend?
你带女朋友一起回来啊
No.
不是啦
Luna, this is Granny Gigi.
露娜 这位是吉吉婆婆
She's the town pharmacist.
她是镇上的药师
She's made a lot of medicines for Manicia.
一直以来为玛妮西娅做了很多药
Let's get along, Luna.
请多指教哦 露娜
Yes…
请…请多指教
She reminds me of how Manicia used to be.
看着她 让我想起了以前的玛妮西娅呢
Yes.
是啊
I wish I could do more to help,
其实我真的很想多帮上一些忙
but medicines alone
但是光凭药物
aren't enough to cure the root of her illness.
实在无法根治她的疾病
You've already done a lot to help us.
您已经很照顾我们了
Thanks to you,
多亏有吉吉婆婆
our lives are much better now.
我们的生活已经比以前还好过了
Is that so?
是吗
And you too, Luna. If you ever need any help,
露娜也是 如果之后遇到什么问题
come to my pharmacy.
可以随时来我家的药房哦
You children are all like my own.
因为你们这些年轻人 就像我的孩子一样
Oh, right.
对了
I'm on my way to harvest some spinach.
我现在要去采菠菜
Would you like to join me?
你们要跟我一起去吗
Rud, you finally brought a woman back?
路德终于带女人回来了
No more sister complex for you?
不当妹控了吗
All right. Behave.
很好 今天不准暴走哦
Sorry.
抱歉啊
It's a small town,
因为这里是个什么都没有的 乡下小镇
so gossip is about the only entertainment around here.
大家唯一的娱乐就是聊八卦
I don't mind.
没事的
Well,
露娜你嘛
it's probably because you look like a sweet girl
可能是因为长得也很端庄
so they can't help but fawn over you.
所以大家才会忍不住格外照顾你吧
Um, no…
不是
Why… Why don't you try some of the magic greens we plucked?
你…你要吃吃看刚才采的魔菜吗
Good… Good idea.
说…说得也是
It's good!
好好吃
I'm glad you like it.
太好了
I'm sure everyone will be happy to hear that.
如果大家听到你这么说 肯定会很高兴的
Avancier is a quiet place
相较于其他城镇
compared to other towns,
阿凡锡亚确实是个很闲静的地方
but I like it here.
但我很喜欢这里
What about you?
你喜欢这里吗
The people here are very kind to me.
这里的人都对我很亲切
I'm glad to be in such a nice place.
我很庆幸 能来到这么好的地方
If I could stay here forever,
要是能永远待在这里
I don't know how happy I would be.
不知道会多么幸福
Do you feel something in my chest?
您有感受到我胸口的东西吗
It's a magic stone, right?
这是魔石…对吧
Yes.
是的
You may not believe it,
您可能不会相信
but I am actually not a human.
但我其实不是人类
I'm a combat-type Homunculus
而是邻国布伦凯斯开发的
developed by the neighbouring country Brunn Quelez.
战斗型人造人
I'm sorry for keeping it from you.
对不起 一直瞒着您
Because I didn't want to say it.
因为我不想说
I was afraid that if people knew I was a Homunculus,
我担心被人知道我是人造人
I would be destroyed.
就会遭到销毁
But
但是
you've helped me so much.
您帮了我这么多
I couldn't keep deceiving you…
要我继续欺骗您 实在太痛苦了
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I've been keeping something from you too.
我也有事瞒着你
Actually, I already figured it out.
其实我早就发现了
That you were a Homunculus.
发现你是人造人
I happened to see
因为当时
the magic stone on you.
我偶然看到了你身上的魔石
So,
那么
why are you still helping me?
您为什么还要帮助我呢
Before coming here,
在来到这里前
Manicia and I used to live in the slums.
我和玛妮西娅曾经在贫民窟生活过
The look in your eyes
而你的眼神
was like Manicia's back then,
和玛妮西娅当时的眼神很像
and I just couldn't leave you alone.
让我无法放任你不管
Even though
但是我们
we lived in a place like that,
即便生活在那种地方
we wanted to live like humans.
也还是希望活得像个人
What about you, Luna?
露娜你呢
Do you want to live like a Homunculus
你想当人造人
or do you want to live like a human?
还是想作为人类活下去呢
Can you tell me
可以告诉我
how you really feel?
你内心真正的想法吗
For a Homunculus like me,
对我这个人造人来说
that's wishful thinking.
那种事并不现实
Is that so?
是吗
I've never heard of a rule that says a Homunculus can't be human.
但我没听说过人造人 不能变成人类啊
Besides,
而且
I've been raiding labyrinths for a similar reason.
我之所以会一直攻略迷宫 也是为了类似的理由
I've been searching for the labyrinth treasure
毕竟我是为了治好玛妮西娅的病
to cure Manicia.
才会不断寻找着 不知道是否存在的迷宫秘宝
We both have unattainable aspirations.
所以说 我们都有着遥不可及的愿望
Don't you think that makes us the perfect friends?
你不觉得这样的我们 很适合成为朋友吗
I…
我…
If it's here…
如果是在这个地方
If it's by his side…
如果是在他的身边
Maybe my wish could really come true…
或许我真的能期待 那个愿望会有实现的一天
I
我…
want to live as a human.
想作为人类活下去
I understand.
我知道了
Let's get along, Luna.
那就再次请你多多指教了 露娜
Yes, Master.
是的 今后请多指教 主人
Wouldn't calling me "Master" be too Homunculus-like?
叫我"主人" 会不会太像人造人了？
Is that so?
会吗
But for some reason,
但是不知道为什么
I wish to call you that.
我就是想这样称呼您呢
I see.
这样啊
Lady Manicia,
玛妮西娅大人
I have something to tell you.
我有话想告诉您
Are you sure about this?
这样好吗
Yes.
是的
I don't want to hide it from people I care about anymore.
因为我不想再对亲近的人 有所隐瞒了
I am a Homunculus.
其实我是人造人
I am very sorry for hiding it from you.
至今以来一直瞒着您 真的很抱歉
So that's why you were a little different.
难怪我觉得你跟一般人不太一样
Will you still
那么以后
be my friend?
你还愿意和我当朋友吗
Of course.
当然愿意
You knew, didn't you, Big Brother?
哥哥早就知道了吧
Reaching your hand out to those in need of help…
伸手协助孤立无援的人
That part of you
哥哥你这点
hasn't changed at all.
还是跟以前一模一样呢
Finally done with the cleaning.
总算扫完了
I'm exhausted.
累死了
I'm starving.
肚子饿了
Thank you for your help, Master.
辛苦您了 主人
Thank you as well.
你也辛苦了
Sorry for making you help with the clean-up too.
不好意思 还让你帮我们一起大扫除
It's not a problem at all.
没事的
Still,
话说回来
this is a huge estate.
这栋房子很大耶
Everyone, I made tea.
各位 茶水已经准备好咯
What?
什么
Tea prepared by Manicia?
玛妮西娅泡的茶？
Lady Manicia is popular indeed.
玛妮西娅大人真受欢迎呢
Huh?
咦
I will be the first to drink Manicia's tea!
我一定要第一个喝到 玛妮西娅泡的茶
Manicia's tea is especially great when I'm the first to get to drink it.
抢头香喝到的 玛妮西娅泡的茶特别好喝呢
It's all the same.
每一杯都一样啦
Rud, your sister complex really knows no bounds.
路德真的是个彻底的妹控呢
I told you to stop saying that.
就叫你别再这么说了
Manicia, how are you feeling?
玛妮西娅 你身体还好吧？
You said you were feeling fine today,
虽然你说今天状况不错
but helping us with the clean-up is still too much.
但你居然还来帮忙打扫 未免太操劳了
All I did was made tea.
我只是帮忙泡个茶而已
Big Brother, you worry too much.
哥哥太爱操心了啦
But…
可是…
My body may be frail,
虽然我确实体弱多病
but I don't want to be a burden to you.
但我不想成为哥哥的绊脚石啊
Manicia…
玛妮西娅
I've told you, haven't I?
之前不是说过很多次了吗
You're never a burden to me.
我从来没有这么认为哦
Oi, Rud!
喂 路德
Since we're done with the clean-up,
既然已经打扫完了
why don't we have a nice spar? It's been a while.
来场久违的决斗吧
A spar?
决…决斗？
It's just a friendly spar.
只是模拟战啦
This is the perfect chance for that.
这样正好
Guys,
各位
can you wait until I've sparred with Fil?
你们可以等我和菲尔打完后再来吗
Me?
我吗
I see.
原来如此
You want to test the effects of your skills
你想透过模拟战
you didn't know about through sparring.
确认未知技能的效果啊
That's right.
没错
If it's against the vice leader of the vigilante corps,
如果是和自警团的副队长
I should be able to go all out.
应该就能放手打一场了
If I weaken your shield force by a great deal, you lose.
只要你的护盾被我大幅削减 就算你输
That works, right?
这个条件可以吧
Sure.
好
Get ready.
预备
Begin!
开始
Neither of them moved.
他们都没有动耶
Well, they're not the kind to win a battle with speed.
因为他们都不是靠速度来战斗的人
But
不过
someone still has to make the first move.
即便如此 还是得有人先行动才行
That's a heavy blow.
好沉重的一击
Fil has gotten a lot stronger
菲尔这家伙
since we last duelled.
变得比以前交手时还强了
That hit could've seriously taken me out.
要是真的挨了这一击 我会输掉
Lady Fil is strong.
菲尔大人好厉害
They may be the vigilante corps,
虽说是自警团
but the members are mostly young townspeople who've never left.
但里面的成员 都是自愿留在镇上的年轻人
So, not everyone is as skilled in combat.
所以并非每个人都这么善战
But
但是
Miss Fil and Big Brother are exceptions.
菲尔小姐和哥哥算是特例
They're better off honing their skills in the big cities.
他们应该要去更大的城市发展才对
I see.
原来是这样啊
Get him, Fil!
冲啊…菲尔
We ought to take Rud down sometimes!
偶尔也打赢路德一次吧
Master!
主人
Please do your best!
加油
Big Brother!
哥哥
You've got a lot of time to be looking around.
你还有闲工夫东张西望啊
It grazed me, but it's not a big deal.
虽然有擦到一下 但没有大碍
I can use this damage…
正好能利用这个伤害…
Rud's off balance.
路德失去平衡了
Fil, now's your chance!
菲尔 趁这个机会把他打倒
What?
什么
My shield force was wiped out.
护盾耗尽了
Just from that one hit?
难道是因为刚才那一击吗
Has that Rud finally learned an attack skill?
路德这家伙 终于也学会攻击技能了吗
Doesn't Fil have a shield force of 2500 or something?
菲尔的护盾不是有2500左右吗
To destroy it in one hit, just how powerful is that skill?
居然能一击耗尽护盾 这技能到底多厉害啊
You've gotten stronger.
你又变强了呢
Still not enough to beat you, though.
不过还是没能打败你呢
By the way,
话说回来
what was that stupendous skill?
刚才那个厉害的技能是什么啊
It's called "Life Conversion".
那招叫"生命转换"
It allows me to turn
是一种能把之前损耗的护盾 转换成力量的技能
I can't use it anytime I want,
虽然不是随时都能用
but thanks to this duel,
不过多亏这场模拟战
I now know how powerful it is.
我才能知道这个攻击技能的威力 居然这么强
Thanks.
谢谢你
Glad to be of help.
很高兴能帮上忙
As a tank,
身为肉盾
I've always been concentrating on defence.
我至今一直致力于防守
However,
不过
thanks to this "Life Conversion" skill,
从今以后 多亏有这个"生命转换"
I'll be able to attack as well.
我也能加入攻击了
All right. Who's next?
好 接下来换谁上？
I just remembered I have an emergency…
我…我突然有急事
I think I have a stomach ache.
哎呀 肚子好痛
Master, you were incredible.
主人 您好厉害哦
Yes.
是啊
Big Brother is amazing.
哥哥真的很厉害
Compared to him, I…
相较之下 我…
Mama… Papa…
妈妈 爸爸
Big Brother…
哥哥
Where are you?
你们去哪里了
It looks like that girl's been abandoned.
那孩子好像被抛弃了耶
I heard she has an incurable disease.
听说是罹患了不治之症
Seems her parents are only willing to keep their son, Rud.
应该是打算只养那个 叫路德的大儿子吧
I saw them drag him away.
我有看到他们把他强行带走了
From the looks of it, she won't last long.
不过看她这样 应该也活不久了吧
Manicia!
玛妮西娅
Thank goodness! So this is where you were.
太好了 原来你在这里啊
Big Brother!
哥哥
It's that dream again.
又是当时那个梦
Big Brother always came back for me.
最后哥哥总是会来找我
But is he really happy like this?
但是 这样哥哥真的幸福吗
If it weren't for me,
如果没有我的话
he would be able to live more freely, wouldn't he?
哥哥应该可以更自由地生活吧